DIVYAN **PARAMASIVAM**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Profile info

I'm a software engineer graduated from Asia Pacific University (APU) and have a strong interest in software architecture. industrial experience in software development catered for financial sector and sets goals on every project that I carry out.

Work Experience

Software Engineer

Silverlake Axis | Petaling Jaya

November 2022-Present

- Designed and developed a stateful SOAP API to handle server-client requests and a facilitating RESTful API integration between a service gateway and the client's backend server for managing payment notifications.
- Contributed to the entire development process of an admin dashboard using the Facilitated the Angular framework. transition from AngularJS to ReactJS for the frontend, while utilizing Spring Boot and Node.js on the backend. Integrated these with a MySQL JDBC database to store and retrieve information regarding API calls.
- Involved in the development of client's payment gateways and web services using WSDL, XSL, XML, SoapUI, and Java which facilitated the integration of backend for payment processing.

Front End Developer Intern

Fusionex International | Petaling Jaya

July 2021-November 2021



Contact

+60-176443872



divyanparam30@gmail.com



₩ LinkedIn

Selangor, Malaysia

Skills

- JavaScript
- · Unit & Integration Testing
- Git
- Analytical Skills
- Leadership & Teamwork
- Adaptable

Interests

- Cloud Computing
- UI/UX Design

- Design web modules based on MEAN stack for web development for project that the team was working on. Worked closely with team to enhance the software's UI/UX design to meet client's demand.
- Carried out software testing with team leader in User Acceptance Testing (UAT) and System Integration Testing (SIT) environments before releasing the final version to clients.

IT Support

West Point Periodicals | May 2019-Klang August 2019

- Worked well independently in a team to solve technical related problems (e.g. hardware and software troubleshooting).
- Organized and prioritized work to complete given tasks in a timely, efficient manner.

Certifications

AWS Cloud Practitioner

Issuer: AWS

References

Koh Thong Kiat

Product Manager @ Silverlake Axis

Education History

September 2019-August 2022 BSc (Hons) in Software Engineering |

Asia Pacific University (APU)

<u>Grade</u>

3.45

<u>Programming Languages</u> Java, Kotlin, C#, C++, R, PHP, JavaScript

Clubs and Societies

- Member of APU Rotaract Club
- Member of APU Beyond Media Team

September 2019-August 2022 BSc (Hons) in Software Engineering |

Staffordshire University

• Dual-degree programme

May 2018-April 2019

Foundation in Computing and Technology |

Asia Pacific University (APU)

• Grade: 3.55

DuitNow Consumer Presented QR & Cross Border QR | Silverlake Axis

May 2023

- Conducted both functional and nonfunctional requirement gathering to tailor host message schema based on client demands.
- Created an interface design document, serving as a key reference for clients during project development.
- Played a key role in backend development for payment processing, accelerating the process by 30% to meet client deadlines.
- Formulated and executed unit test cases for System Integration Testing (SIT), ensuring seamless end-to-end functionality using SOAPUI simulator and reducing the likelihood of errors in the UAT environment by 70%.
- Provided 2-3 months of User Acceptance Testing (UAT) and Production (BAU) support, ensuring a smooth transition and addressing any potential issues postdevelopment.

Blood Bank and Donor Management Web Application |

Asia Pacific University (APU)

August 2022

- Created a web application for nationwide blood bank system management, incorporating real-time GPS tracking to locate the nearest blood bank.
- Utilized PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS for the development of the application.